PROFILE

Producer, journalist, and media professional with 4+ years of experience. A generous, on-top-of-it and innovative communicator with strong leadership skills in both large and small teams. Work featured with Netflix, Delta Airlines, The Sartorial Geek, SpaceX, Boeing, Rocket Crafters, and at the Smithsonian Institute.

2020 ScreenCraft Quarterfinalist

2020 <u>Ashland New Plays Festival</u> Inaugural Pass the Pen Finalist

2021 **Women & Science Festival Finalist**In association with Central Square Theatre and MIT

2020/2021 A4 Artist-in-Residence

PROJECTS

Peace and Progress aboard the ISS

Supercluster | A24 Films

Pitched and developed an editorial campaign featuring interviews with former astronaut Nicole Stott and NASA flight director Pooja Jesrani.

Article went viral on Reddit's r/space, hitting **36.3K+** upvotes in two days.

#LaunchAmerica

Supercluster | SpaceX

Managed live social coverage of the historic Crew Dragon DM-2 mission to the ISS on Twitter and Facebook.

Social content went viral on Facebook, hitting **1K+** likes and **200+** shares on our most popular content. Grew follower base by 5%.

Real Astronaut | Play Astronaut

Supercluster | A24 Films

Executive producer of the new Supercluster exclusive series connecting real life astronauts with the astronauts of the small and silver screens, Real Astronaut | Play Astronaut. Inaugural episode featured Felicity Jones and David Oyelowo for Netflix's The Midnight Sky. Negotiated contracts and scheduling with Netflix and R&CPMK. Project led to R&CMPK offering an exclusive interview with Joel Kinnaman, establishing a working relationship with executives at Apple TV+.

EDUCATION

New York University - Tisch

BFA in Drama

GPA: 3.78, Magna Cum Laude F16 + S18 Dean's List

ALEXANDRALINHOLDEN@GMAIL.COM

ALEXANDRA LIN HOLDEN

MEDIA PROFESSIONAL

EXPERIENCE

Head Writer + Producer* Supercluster | A24 Films 2018 – present New York, NY

Producer of the Supercluster podcast. Responsible for pitching, scripting, scheduling, recording, and editing podcast episodes. Profiles leading figures in space and popular culture, including former Livestream CEO/Launcher CEO Max Haot, former astronauts Dr. Mike Massimino and Nicole Stott, Associate Administrator of Human Exploration and Operations Kathy Lueders, Joel Kinnaman, Cathy Ang, Felicity Jones, Ming-Na Wen, and David Oyelowo. Writes editorials averaging 1,600 - 2,000 words for a Millennial/Gen-Z demographic. Drafts social media copy for Twitter/Facebook covering breaking news and engaging with popular culture, in addition to facilitating live coverage of launches to a follower base of 500K-1M. Manages relationships with 15+ different cross-industry entities, including academic institutions (CalTech, UCLA), government agencies (NASA), and production companies (Netflix, Apple TV+).

*Portfolio available at alexandralinholden.com/portfolio

Film/TV Editor Screen Rant 2017 – 2018 New York, NY

Freelance editor who curates and pitches new content covering the latest trends, releases, and developments in the film and TV industries for a leading online entertainment news site with an audience of **7.7M**. Organizes and edits contributor posts through WordPress. Responsible for **15+** individual pieces of content a week and tagging appropriate SEO keywords to optimize each article's relevance in Google searches. Develops content strategy for upcoming Netflix releases, which includes: managing the content calendar, conducting interviews with talent and production teams, and analyzing subsequent data and engagement for reference in future strategies.

Independent Producer
Actors Theatre of Louisville

2019 – 2020 Louisville, KY

Founded the actor-led production company, the Take Sweet Action Collective, while serving as an acting apprentice. Facilitated cross-department meetings between lights, sound, house management, festival and events, and production management. Organized cabarets and staged readings featuring local and guest artists.

SKILLS

Adobe suite, Microsoft Office Suite, HTML5, CSS3, Python, Git, GitHub, GitLab,, FinalCut Pro, ProTools, Tableau, SEO, Slack, CMS (WordPress, MS SharePoint), classical pianist for 10+ years, makes a real mean Sichuanstyle fried chicken.

REFERENCES

Robin Seemangal - Supercluster - Chief of Content | robin@supercluster.com Mary Baldino - Rocket Crafters - Media Manager | mary.baldino@rocketcrafters.com Pirronne Yousefzadeh - Geva Theatre - Associate Artistic Director | pirronne@gmail.com